Guide to the Eunice Johnson Collection on Timothy Richard)
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Collected Research Resources, 1876-2007; Series II
  - Writings Related to Timothy Richard
    - Newspaper Clippings, Articles, and Book Chapters, 1884-2000
      - "British Missions Falling Behind in China", 1899 Apr (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Editorial: "A Step Forward in China", 1900 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - "China Public School," North China Herald, 1900, 1905, 1906 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - The Society for the Diffusion of Christian and General Knowledge, Jan 1900 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - "A Public School for Chinese in Shanghai", 1900 Apr (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - "China Old and New I and II", 1900 Aug (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - "Quoad Hoc, Letter re a Missionary Executive", 1900 Nov (Box 6, Folder 34)
      - D.D. Brown University, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 35)
      - London Times, 1901-1907 (Box 6, Folder 36)
      - News Clippings, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 37)
      - Shanxi Martyr Memorials, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 38)
      - Letter: "A Million Converts", 1901 Sep (Box 6, Folder 39)
      - "The Rev. Timothy Richard, D.D., D.Lit., of China: An Appreciation", 1901 (Box 6, Folder 40)
      - News Clippings, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 41)
      - The Chi-nan-fu College, May 1902 (Box 6, Folder 42)
      - Government Universities, Sep 1902 (Box 6, Folder 43)
      - News Clippings, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 44)
      - Martyrs' Memorial for China, Nov 1903 (Box 6, Folder 45)
      - New Clippings, 1904 (Box 6, Folder 46)
      - "The Imperial University, Shansi," by Moir Duncan, 1904 (Box 6, Folder 47)
      - "The Rev. Timothy Richard," by Fred Price, 1904 (Box 6, Folder 48)
      - "The Imperial University at Taiyuenfu, Shansi," by L.R.O. Bevan, 1904-1905 (Box 6, Folder 49)
      - International Red Cross Society, 1904 Mar (Box 6, Folder 50)
      - News Clippings, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - "The Fate of China: A Chat with Rev. Dr. Timothy Richard", 1905 Mar 23 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - "The Awakening of China: Dr. Timothy Richard's Visit to Cheltenham", 1906 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - "The Future of Missions: A Prophet's Forecast", 1906 Feb 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - "China and the West", 1906 Mar 10 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - "The Awakening of China", 1906 Apr 21 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - "Dr. Timothy Richard", 1906 May 19 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - News Clippings, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - "Conversion by the Million", 1907 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - "Educational Resolutions Adopted by the Centenary Missionary Conference", 1907 Jun (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Journal of the North-China Branch of the Royal Asiatic Society re:Timothy Richard, 1907, 1912, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - London Times - Timothy Richard, 1907-1919 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Calendar of the Imperial University of Shansi (Western Department), 1908 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - "One of China's Scholars: The Early Life and Conversion of Pastor Hsi" by Mrs. Howard Taylor, 1908 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - News Clippings, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - News Clippings, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - World Missionary Conference. Report of Commission IV: "The Missionary Message in Relation to Non-Christian Religions", 1910 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - News Clippings, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - "Christian Literature and the Reform Movement in China", 1911 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - "Dr. Timothy Richard and Shansi University", 1911 Jul (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - News Clippings, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Det Nya Kina (The New China): Shansi Universitetet, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Honorary Degrees, 1913, 1916 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - News Clippings, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - Christian Literature Society: Resolution, 14 Dec 1914 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - News Clippings, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Retirement, 1916 (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - University of Wales: Program - Congregation of the University for Admission to Degrees, 1916 Jul 15 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - Reviews: Forty-five Years in China, 1916-1917 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Couling, Samuel. The Encyclopedia Sinica, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - "To Hasten the Kingdom of God in All Lands": Prize Essay, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - "Resolution: Rev. Timothy Richard, D.D., D.Litt.," by M.T. Jones, 1917 Jan 25 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - "Li-it-mo-tai of China. The Story of a Great Life" by Nelson Britton, 1917 May (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - News Clippings, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      - "A Foster Father of the League of Nations" by Eleanor Richard, 1919 Mar (Box 7, Folder 35)
      - Timothy Richard Obituaries and Memorials, 1919 Apr (Box 7, Folder 36)
      - Minute by the Central Committee of the Christian Literature Society for China, 1919 May (Box 7, Folder 37)
      - Annual Meeting of the Christian Literature Society (notes), 1919 May (Box 7, Folder 38)
      - Letter: "Dr. Timothy Richard" by C. S. Medhurst, 1919 May 3 (Box 7, Folder 39)
      - Rev. Timothy Richard, LL.D., D.Lit.: A Missionary Monograph, 1919 Jun (Box 7, Folder 40)
      - The New China Review. Portrait, Notes and Queries, Jul 1919 (Box 7, Folder 41)
      - BMS. Timothy Richard, D.D., Litt.D., LL.D., 1919 (Box 7, Folder 42)
      - Obituary: "Timothy Richard" by G. McIntosh, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 43)
      - Obituary: "Timothy Richard" by Evan Morgan, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 44)
      - "Timothy Richard, D.D., Litt.D., LL.D.: An Outline of His Life and Work in China" by Hilda Bowser, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 45)
      - Nécrologie: "Timothy Richard" by Henri Cordier., 1920 (Box 7, Folder 46)
      - "Det Nyaste Kina" by Erik Nystrom, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 47)
      - A Century of Christian Conquest in Cathay, 1836-1936. Records and Address of the China Baptist Centenary Celebrations Tung Shan, Canton, China 10/13-10/18/36 (select chapters) (Box 7, Folder 48)
      - The Rev. Watson McMillen Hayes, D.D., LL.D. Memorial Minute, 1944 Oct 16 (Box 7, Folder 49)
      - "China and Timothy Richard" by H. R. Williamson, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 50)
      - "The Centenary of Timothy Richard; Timothy Richard: His Contribution to Modern China" by E. W. Burt, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 51)
      - "Timothy Richard, Missionary and Mandarin: A Centenary Tribute" by H. J. Cowell, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 52)
      - "The Man Who Could Not be Denied", 1945 (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - Timothy Richard Centenary, 1945 Oct 10 (Box 7, Folder 54)
      - The Great Succession. Chapter IX. Timothy Richard of China 1845-1919 by E. A. Payne, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 55)
      - "Timothy Richard" (Chinese) by Kang Youwei, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 56)
      - These Sought a Country. Chapter IV. Timothy Richard: He Sought All China by Kenneth Scott Latourette, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 57)
      - Ma Kuan I-Ho-Ch'ien Li-Ti Mo-Tai Li Hung-Chang te Mai Kuo Yin Mo (Chinese) by Ting Tse-Liang., 1951 (Box 7, Folder 58)
      - "Timothy Richard 1845-1919" by H. R. Williamson, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - "The Glorious Company: Lives of Great Christians for Daily Devotion: Timothy Richard" by Frederick C. Gill, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 60)
      - Shanxi University (Chinese), 1962-1963, 1982, 1991, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 61)
      - Chronological Outline of Timothy Richard's Life, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 62)
      - Papers on China: Re Timothy Richard, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 63)
      - "Mrs. Moir Duncan: One of the Pioneers" by Olive Mary Coats, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 64)
      - "To China with Love: The Life and Times of Protestant Missionaries in China, 1860-1900" by Pat Barr, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - International Bulletin of Missionary Research, 1983, 1993, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - "A Comparative Approach to the Cultural Dynamics of Sino-Western Educational Co-operation" by Ruth E.S. Hayhoe, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Crucible of Modern China. Chapter X. From Enlightenment to Revolution by Betty Wei, Betty, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - " The Contested Past: The Boxers as History and Myth" by Paul A. Cohen, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Historical Dictionary of Revolutionary China, 1839-1976, p.174-177, 198-201, 306-307, 324-325, 382-383, by Edwin Pak-wah Leung, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Verbiest Courier, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Christian History, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - "Timothy Richard and the Chinese Reform Movement" by Timothy Man-Kong Wong, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - "The Legacy of Timothy Richard" by Paul Bohr Paul., 2000 Apr (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - "Course of Study and Examination Scheme as Arranged by the Educational Association and the Diffusion Society" (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - "Our Standard Bearers" by Harry L. Hemmens (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Collected Articles Related to Timothy Richard, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Newspaper Clippings Related to Timothy Richard, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Theses and Manuscripts by Others Related to Timothy Richard, 1910-2007
      - Cheng, Chen Wei. "The Education Work of Missionaries in China." University of Michigan, 1910 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Hoh, Yam Tong. "The Boxer Indemnity Remissions and Education in China". Columbia University, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Chu, You Kuang." Some Problems of a National System of Education in China." Columbia University, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Lund, Renville Clifton. "The Imperial University of Peking." University of Washington, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 17a)
      - Wang, Shu-Hwai. "The Educational Association of China 1890-1912: Its History and Meaning in the Missionary Education in China". University of Hawaii, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Johnson, Rita T.: "Timothy Richard's Theory of Christian Missions to the Non-Christian World." St. John's University, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 1a)
      - Kikuchi, Bert Hideo: "Timothy Richard's Influence on the Missionary Movement and Chinese Reform in Lat Chi'ing China." University of Oregon, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 1b)
      - Wright, Daniel B.:"J. Hudson Taylor 1832-1905 and Timothy Richard 1845-1919: Two Unique Tools for God's Task in China", 1987 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Xu, Xiaoguang. "A Southern Methodist Mission to China: Soochow University, 1901-1939." Middle Tennessee State University, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 2a)
      - Sun, Lung-kee: "Liang Qichao and Social Psychology". Memphis State University, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Chen, Xiaoqing: "A Study of the Intellectual Foundations of Various Disciplines at Peking University, 1910s-1930s." University of Wisconsin, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Xu, Xiaoguang: "A Great Educational Practice in Modern China: Vanderbilt Graduates in Soochow University, 1900-1930", 1994 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Yoo, Il-Sung: "A Comparative Study of Hudson Taylorof the CIM with Special Reference to Evangelism by Nationwide Spread of the Gospel through Direct Proclamation, 1865-1900 and Timothy Richard of the BMS with Special Reference to Evangelism by National Reform, Focusing Especially on "Worthy Men", 1891-1914." Trinity College, Bristol, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 5a)
      - Pfister, Lauren: "Re-thinking Mission in China: James Hudson Taylor and Timothy Richard." University of Cambridge, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Kaiser, Andrew T.: "A History of Protestant Missions in Shanxi." Shanxi Evergreen Service, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Ng, Peter Tze Ming: "Timothy Richard: Chrisitan Attitudes towards Chinese Religions and Culture." Henry Martyn Lectures, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 1a)
      - Chen, Xiaoqing Diana: "The Development of Modern Chinese Intelligentsia and the Appropriation of Foreign Educational Models (1900-1920s)" (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Harrison, Henrietta: "Newspapers and Nationalism in the Shanxi Countryside, 1890-1928." St. Anne's College, University of Oxford (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Stephens, Margaret Anne. "The Impact of the West: Timothy Richard and Reform in China." George Washington University, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 1c)
    - Books and Pamphlets, 1872-2002
      - Clarke, James Freeman. Ten Great Religions. Boston: James R. Osgood and Company, 1872 (Box 10, Folder 3a)
      - Nevius, John L. China and the Chinese. Philadelphia: Presbyterian Board of Publication, 1882 (Box 10, Folder 3b)
      - The Anti-foreign Riots in China in 1891. Shanghai: North China Herald Office (photocopy), 1892 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Brown, J. Cummings. The Awakening of China. Edinburgh: Andrew Elliot (photocopy), 1897 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Chih-Tung, Chang, translated by Samuel I. Woodbridge. China's Only Hope: An Appeal. Edinburgh; London: Oliphant, Anderson & Ferrier, 1901 (Box 10, Folder 5a)
      - Wong, Theodore. Chronological tables of the Chinese dynasties (from the Chow Dynasty to the Ch'ing Dynasty). Shanghai: Shanghai Printing Company, 1902 (Box 10, Folder 5b)
      - Mako Fuh-Yin (Mandarin: Gospel of Mark). Shanghai: British and Foreign Bible Society, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Matai Fuh-Yin (Mandarin: Gospel of Matthew). Shanghai: British and Foreign Bible Society, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Edwards, E.H. Fire and Sword in Shansi: The Story of the Martyrdom of Foreigners and Chinese Christians. Edinburgh; London: Oliphant, Anderson & Ferrier, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 7a)
      - Reeve, B. Timothy Richard, D.D.: China Missionary Statesman and Reformer. London: S.W. Partridge & Co. Ltd. (photocopy), ca.1911 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Headland, Isaac Taylor. China's New Day: A Study of Events that have Led to its Coming. West Medford, MA: Central Committee on the United Study of Missions, 1912 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Nyström, Erik T. The Coal and Mineral Resources of Shansi Province, China. Stockholm: Kungl. Boktryckeriet. P.A. Norstedt & Söner (photocopy), 1912 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Pott, F.L. Hawks. The Emergency in China. New York: Missionary Education Movement of the United States and Canada, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Beckman, E.R. The Massacre at Sianfu: And Other Experiences in Connection with the Scandinavian Alliance Mission of North America. Chicago: E.R. Beckman, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Morthensen, Eilert. En Veteran: Nogle Blade af Chinas Missionshistorie. København: Det Danske Missionsselskab (photocopy), 1914 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - MacGillivray, D., Timothy Richard of China: A Prince in Israel. Shanghai: Christian Literature Society (photocopy), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Soothill, William E. Timothy Richard of China: Seer, Statesman, Missionary and the Most Disinterested Adviser the Chinese Ever Had. London: Seeley, Service & Co. Limited (photocopy), 1924 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Glover, Archibald E. A Thousand Miles of Miracle in China: A Personal Record of God's Delivering Power from the Hands of the Imperial Boxers of Shan-si. London: Pickering & Inglis Ltd., 1944 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Evans, E.W. Price. Timothy Richard: A Narrative of Christian Enterprise and Statesmanship in China. London: Carey Press, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Garnier, Albert J. A Maker of Modern China. London: Carey Press, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Holloway, Brenda W. Timothy Richard of China: A Pageant. London: Carey Press (photocopy), 1945 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Warr, Winifred. Far into China: The Story of Timothy Richard, Pioneer (photocopy), 1945 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - TseLiang, Ting. Li Ti Mo Tai (Timothy Richard: A Typical Missionary in Service of Imperialism) (photocopy), 1951 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Bohr, Paul Richard. Famine in China and the Missionary. Cambridge: East Asian Research Center, Harvard University, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Brandt, Nat.: Massacre in Shans i. Syracuse, NY: Syracuse University Press, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Tucker, Rev. L.: Notes on the Life and Work of Dr. Timothy Richard, of China. London: John F. Shaw & Co., Ltd. (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Chinese language books related to Timothy Richard (5 books), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Chinese language books related to Shanxi University and Timothy Richard (6 books), ca. 2002 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Microfilm and Microfiche
      - Baptist Missionary Society Archives. Missionary Journals and Correspondence 1792-1914. Reels 57-60, 1869-1914 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Baptist Missionary Society Archives. Missionary Correspondence China. Timothy Richard (4 Reels), 1869-1914 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Ch'iu Ch'ang Ch'un. A Mission to Heaven. Shanghai (2 copies), 1913 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - D. Wyre Lewis Papers. Timothy Richard Group. Correspondence (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - North China Herald. Shanghai. Vol. 64-69 (3 Reels), Jan 1900-Dec 1902 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Protestant Missionary Works in Chinese. Harvard-Yenching Library, selected microfiche, various (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Reeve, Benjamin. Timothy Richard, ca.1911 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Timothy Richard Circulars and Pamphlets, 1891-190? (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Books by and about Timothy Richard (1 Reel and 1 Microfiche) (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Eunice Johnson Papers, 1867-2002; Series III
  - Writings and Notes, 1990-2002
    - Note cards, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - "Timothy Richard: Visionary Founder of the Imperial University of Shansi", 1990 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - "Bringing Western Learning to the Literati: Timothy Richard's Contributions to Educational Reform in China, 1870-1916" (prepared for submission to the Woodrow Wilson Foundation for consideration for the Spencer Dissertation Year Fellowship, 1992-1993, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - "Educational Reform in China, 1880-1910: Timothy Richard and his Vision for Higher Education"( Dissertation, Graduate School of the University of Florida), 2001 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Presentation notes and photograph of Eunice Johnson, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - "The Chinese Enlightenment: Timothy Richard's Contributions to Educational Reform in China, 1870-1910" (Prospectus), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Research Correspondence, 1991-2002
    - Allenson, Robert, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - American Baptist Historical Society, 1993-1994 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - ATLA, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Baptist Union of Wales, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Bays, Daniel H., 1991 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Bohr, Richard, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Brown University, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Chen, Diana, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Chinese Information and Cultural Center, 1991, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Emory University, 1991, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Friberg, Håkan, 1994, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Hayhoe, Ruth, 1991-1999 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - McClure, Robert, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Missionary Archives, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Napier, Lennox A.H., 1993 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - National Archives - Red Cross, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - National Library of Wales, 1991-1993 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - News International - London Times, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Overseas Ministries Study Center, 1991-1994 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Overseas Missionary Fellowship, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Peng-yuan, Chang, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Presbyterian Church (USA), Department of History, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Raymer, Doreen (includes photograph), 1991-1999 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Read, Gerald, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Regent's Park College, 1991-1993 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Richard's Family (includes photographs and family tree), 1991-1995 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Salomon, Hillel, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Shanxi University (Guo Guichun, President), 2002 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Shi Jinghuan, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - School of Oriental and African Studies (London), 1991 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Southern Baptist Historical Library and Archives, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Teachers College, Columbia University, Special Collections, Milbank Memorial Library, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - University of California, Berkley, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - University of Wales, 1991-1995 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Waldron, Arthur, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Walters, T.I., 1995 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Whyte, Bob, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - West, Robert (International Scholars Publications), 1994 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Xu, Xiaoguang (Special Collections, Heard Library, Vanderbilt University), 1994 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Yale Divinity School Library, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Collected Dissertation Correspondence, 1991-1997 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Source Guides and Bibliographies, 1867-1997
    - American Baptist Historical Society: Timothy Richard Bibliography, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - American Baptist Historical Society: A Baptist Bibliography, by Edward C. Starr, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Asian Rare Books, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Association for Asian Studies, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - ATLA Religion Database, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Baptist Authors: A Manual of Bibliography, by W.E. McIntyre, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Baptist Missionary Society: Archives Index, Timothy Richard (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Baptist Missionary Society: Missionary Herald list of Timothy Richard items, 1869-1905 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - BIB Search, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Bibliotheca Sinica, by Henri Cordier, 1905-1906, 1922-1924 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - British Sources, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Catalog of Protestant Missionary Works in Chinese, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - China Missions Group, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Chinese Materials Center and Chinese Materials Center and Research Aids Service Center: Booklist, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Chinese Recorder Index (selected pages), 1867-1941 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Chinese Studies in History, 1977-1993 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Center for Research Libraries Handbook, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Christianity in China: A Scholars' Guide to Resources in the Libraries and Archives of the United States, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - A Classified Index to the Chinese Literature of the Protestant Churches in China, by Rev. G.A. Clayton (photocopy), 1918 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Descriptive and Classified Missionary Centenary Catalogue of Current Christian Literature, D. MacGillivray (photocopy), 1907 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Ecclesiastical History: "The Churches Overseas", n.d. (Box 18, Folder 1a)
    - Enoki, Kazuo. "Dr. G.E. Morrison and the Toyo Bunko" (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Interlibrary Loan Returns, 1991-1994 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - JANUS: China and Missions Search (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Japanese Studies of Modern China Since 1953: A Bibliographical Guide to Historical and Social Science Research on the Nineteenth and Twentieth Centuries (photocopies of selected pages), 1975 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Kikuchi Bib., 1969 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - LUIS bibliographical searches, 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Maryknoll - Sources, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Missions-China: Various Bibliographies, 1989, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - New York Public Library: Bibliography Cards, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Notes on Timothy Richard's career, 1887-1919 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - OMF - Sources, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Peterson's Guide to Graduate Programs: Missions and Missiology; Pastoral Ministry and Counseling, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Poole's Index to Periodical Literature (photocopies of selected pages), 1906 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Protestant Missionary Works in Chinese, Harvard-Yenching Library, Harvard University on microfiche, 1st catalogue, Compiled by John Yung-Hsiang Lai, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Reader's Guide to Periodical Literature (photocopies of selected pages), 1890-1918 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Recent Japanese Studies of Modern Chinese History (II): Translations from Shigaku zasshi for 1983-1986, by Joshua A. Fogel, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Religious Books 1876-1982 Index - Missions-China (Box 18, Folder 18)